Humans in the developed world
البشر في العالم المتقدم
spend more than 90 percent of their lives indoors,
يقضون أكثر من 90 في المئة من حياتهم داخل المباني،
where they breathe in and come into contact
حيث يتنفسون داخلا ويحتكون
with trillions of life forms invisible to the naked eye:
بتريليونات من أشكال حياة غير مرئية للعين المجردة:
microorganisms.
كائنات دقيقة.
Buildings are complex ecosystems
المباني هي أنظمة بيئية معقدة
that are an important source
التي تشكل مصدرا أساسيا
of microbes that are good for us,
للميكروبات التي تنفعنا،
and some that are bad for us.
وبعض التي تضرنا.
What determines the types and distributions
ما الذي يحدد أنواع وتوزيعات
of microbes indoors?
الميكروبات داخل المباني؟
Buildings are colonized by airborne microbes
المباني محتلة من طرف ميكروبات تنتقل جوا
that enter through windows
تدخل عن طريق النوافذ
and through mechanical ventilation systems.
وعن طريق أنظمة التهوية الميكانيكية.
And they are brought inside
ويتم جلبها داخلا
by humans and other creatures.
من طرف البشر وكائنات أخرى.
The fate of microbes indoors
مصير ميكروبات ما داخل المباني
depends on complex interactions
يعتمد على تفاعلات معقدة
with humans,
مع البشر،
and with the human-built environment.
ومع البيئة التي صممها البشر .
And today, architects and biologists
واليوم، المعماريون وعلماء الأحياء
are working together
يعملون معا
to explore smart building design
لتحري تصميم بناء ذكي
that will create
سينشئ
healthy buildings for us.
مباني صحية لنا.
We spend an extraordinary amount of time
نقضي مددا زمنية استثنائية
in buildings
في مباني
that are extremely controlled environments,
هي عبارة عن بيئات تحت رقابة شديدة،
like this building here --
مثل هذا المبنى هنا --
environments that have mechanical ventilation systems
مباني تتوفر على أنظمة تهوية ميكانيكية
that include filtering,
تشمل التصفية،
heating and air conditioning.
التسخين وتكييف الهواء.
Given the amount of time that we spend indoors,
وبالنظر إلى مقدار الوقت الذي نقضيه داخل المباني،
it's important to understand
من المهم أن نفهم
how this affects our health.
كيف يؤثر هذا على صحتنا.
At the Biology and the Built Environment Center,
في مركز علم الأحياء و بيئة المباني،
we carried out a study in a hospital
أجرينا دراسة في مستشفى
where we sampled air
حيث أخذنا عينات من الهواء
and pulled the DNA
وسحبنا الحمض النووي
out of microbes in the air.
من الميكروبات في الهواء.
And we looked at three different types of rooms.
ونظرنا إلى ثلاثة أنواع مختلفة من الغرف.
We looked at rooms that were mechanically ventilated,
نظرنا إلى غرف بتهوية ميكانيكية،
which are the data points in the blue.
والتي هي نقاط البينات بالأزرق.
We looked at rooms that were naturally ventilated,
نظرنا إلى غرف بتهوية طبيعية،
where the hospital let us turn off the mechanical ventilation
حيث سمح لنا المستشفى بإطفاء التهوية الميكانيكية
in a wing of the building
في جناح من المبنى
and pry open the windows
والتطفل بفتح النوافذ
that were no longer operable,
التي لم تعد قابلة للتشغيل،
but they made them operable for our study.
لكنهم جعلوها تعمل من أجل دراستنا.
And we also sampled the outdoor air.
وقمنا أيضا بأخذ عينة من الهواء الطلق.
If you look at the x-axis of this graph,
إن نظرتم إلى المحور الأفقي لهذا الرسم البياني،
you'll see that what we commonly want to do --
سترون أن ما نريد عادة أن نقوم به --
which is keeping the outdoors out --
والذي هو ترك ما الهواء الطلق خارجا --
we accomplished that with mechanical ventilation.
قد أنجزنا ذلك من خلال التهوية الميكانيكية.
So if you look at the green data points,
وبالتالي حين تنظرون إلى النقاط الخضراء،
which is air that's outside,
والتي هي الهواء الطلق،
you'll see that there's a large amount of microbial diversity,
سترون أن هناك كميات كبيرة من التنوع الميكروبي،
or variety of microbial types.
أو أنواع مختلفة من الجراثيم.
But if you look at the blue data points,
لكن حين تنظرون إلى نقاط البيانات الزرقاء،
which is mechanically ventilated air,
والذي هو الجو المهوى ميكانيكيا،
it's not as diverse.
ليست بذلك التنوع.
But being less diverse
لكن كونها أقل تنوعا
is not necessarily good for our health.
ليس بالضرورة أمرا جيدا لصحتنا.
If you look at the y-axis of this graph,
إن نظرتم إلى المحور الرأسي لهذا الرسم البياني،
you'll see that, in the mechanically ventilated air,
سترون أنه، في الجو المهوى ميكانيكيا،
you have a higher probability
لدينا احتمالية أعلى
of encountering a potential pathogen,
في مواجهة عوامل مرضية محتملة،
or germ,
أو جراثيم،
than if you're outdoors.
من لو كنا في الهواء الطلق.
So to understand why this was the case,
وبالتالي حتى نفهم لماذا كان الأمر كذلك
we took our data
أخذنا بياناتنا
and put it into an ordination diagram,
ووضعناها في مخطط تنسيق،
which is a statistical map
والذي هو خريطة إحصائية
that tells you something
تخبرنا بشيء
about how related the microbial communities are
حول مدى ترابط المجتمعات الميكروبية
in the different samples.
في العينات المختلفة.
The data points that are closer together
نقاط البيانات المتجاورة
have microbial communities that are more similar
لديها مجتمعات ميكروبية أكثر تشابها
than data points that are far apart.
من نقاط البيانات المتباعدة.
And the first things that you can see from this graph
وأول ما يمكن أن نراه في هذا الرسم البياني
is, if you look at the blue data points,
هو، حين تنظرون إلى نقاط البيانات الزرقاء،
which are the mechanically ventilated air,
والذي هو الجو المهوى ميكانيكيا،
they're not simply a subset of the green data points,
ليست مجرد مجموعة فرعية لنقاط البيانات الخضراء،
which are the outdoor air.
والذي هو جو الهواء الطلق.
What we've found is that mechanically ventilated air
الذي وجدناه في هذا الجو المهوى ميكانيكيا
looks like humans.
يبدو مثل البشر.
It has microbes on it
توجد فيه ميكروبات
that are commonly associated with our skin
تربط عادة بجلدنا
and with our mouth, our spit.
وبفمنا، لعابنا.
And this is because
وهذا بسبب
we're all constantly shedding microbes.
أننا نذرف الميكروبات باستمرار.
So all of you right now
وبالتالي جميعكم الآن
are sharing your microbes with one another.
تتشاركون ميكروباتكم مع بعضكم البعض.
And when you're outdoors,
وحين تكونون في الهواء الطلق،
that type of air has microbes
ذلك النوع من الهواء يتوفر على ميكروبات
that are commonly associated with plant leaves and with dirt.
ترتبط عادة بأوراق النباتات والتراب.
Why does this matter?
لماذا يهمنا هذا الأمر؟
It matters because the health care industry
يهمنا لأن قطاع الرعاية الصحية
is the second most energy intensive industry
هو ثاني أكثر القطاعات استهلاكا للطاقة
in the United States.
في الولايات المتحدة الأمريكية.
Hospitals use two and a half times
تستخدم المستشفيات ضعفين ونصف
the amount of energy as office buildings.
مقدار الطاقة في المباني المكتبية.
And the model that we're working with
والنموذج الذي نشتغل به
in hospitals,
في المستشفيات،
and also with many, many different buildings,
وكذلك في الكثير والكثير من المباني المختلفة،
is to keep the outdoors out.
من أجل ترك الهواء الطلق خارجا.
And this model
وهذا النموذج
may not necessarily be the best for our health.
قد لا يكون بالضرورة الأفضل لصحتنا.
And given the extraordinary amount
وبالنظر إلى الكميات الإستثنائية
of nosocomial infections,
لعدوى المستشفيات،
or hospital-acquired infections,
أو الإلتهابات المكتسبة في المستشفى،
this is a clue that it's a good time
وهذا دليل على أنه وقت مناسب
to reconsider our current practices.
لإعادة النظر في ممارساتنا الحالية.
So just as we manage national parks,
وبالتالي وكما ندير المتنزهات الوطنية،
where we promote the growth of some species
حيث نعزز نمو بعض الأنواع
and we inhibit the growth of others,
ونكبح نمو الأخرى،
we're working towards thinking about buildings
نحن نعمل من أجل التفكير حول البنايات
using an ecosystem framework
باستعمال إطار نظام بيئي
where we can promote the kinds of microbes
حيث يمكن أن نعزز أنواع من الميكروبات
that we want to have indoors.
التي نريدها داخل المباني.
I've heard somebody say
لقد سمعت أحدهم يقول
that you're as healthy as your gut.
أنك تكون صحيحا بقدر صحة أمعائك.
And for this reason, many people eat probiotic yogurt
ولهذا السبب، يتناول الكثير من الناس زبادي حيوي بدائي
so they can promote a healthy gut flora.
بحيث يمكنهم تعزيز نباتات سليمة الأمعاء.
And what we ultimately want to do
وما نريد في النهاية القيام به
is to be able to use this concept
هو أن نكون قادرين على استخدام هذا المفهوم
to promote a healthy group
لترويج مجموعة صحية
of microorganisms inside.
من الكائنات الدقيقة داخليا.
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)